Parodies, [ca. 1850-1950] PN6110 .P3
Lilly Library
Parodies: a collection of several hundred ridiculous rhymes in imitation of known authors and their works
[ca. 1850-1950]
Lilly Library
PN6110 .P3
476 Items
This is a collection of several hundred ridiculous rhymes in imitation of known authors and their works. It includes parodies of Thomas Moore, Rudyard Kipling, Henry Wadsworth Longfellow, Edgar Allan Poe, Alfred Tennyson and William Shakespeare, among others.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Historical Note
A parody (also called a spoof, send-up, take-off, or lampoon) is a work created to imitate, make fun of, or comment on an original work—its subject, author, style, or some other target—by means of satiric or ironic imitation. This collection includes literary parodies of works by authors including Thomas Moore, Rudyard Kipling, Henry Wadsworth Longfellow, Edgar Allan Poe, Alfred Tennyson and William Shakespeare. No attempt has been made to research or verify name forms, titles, or authorship for this preliminary listing.
Arrangement
The parodies are arranged alphabetically by author parodied.
On the envelopes, red entries reflect what appear to be the collector's indications of the author and/or the work being parodied. Red asterisks indicate that a copy of all or part of the work apparently being parodied is included. Black entries reflect what appear to be titles, first lines, and authors of parodies; black entries in quotation marks appear to be first lines of parodies.
Scope and Content Note
This is a collection of several hundred ridiculous rhymes in imitation of known authors and their works. It includes parodies of Thomas Moore, Rudyard Kipling, Henry Wadsworth Longfellow, Edgar Allan Poe, Alfred Tennyson and William Shakespeare, among others. This is a first listing of a collection underwritten by George Ball and received at Lilly Library during the school year 1955-1956. No attempt has been made to research or verify name forms, titles, or authorship for this preliminary listing. It is only a primitive finding aid for the user and a record of the collector's notes taken from his envelopes which had to be removed from the materials.
Acquisition Information
Acquired: 1956
Provenance
The collection was underwritten by George Ball and received at Lilly Library during the school year 1955-1956
Parodies.; Poetry --Collections.; Moore, Thomas, 1779-1852 --Parodies, imitations, etc.; Kipling, Rudyard, 1865-1936 --Parodies, imitations, etc.; Longfellow, Henry Wadsworth, 1807-1882 --Parodies, imitations, etc.; Poe, Edgar Allan, 1809-1849 --Parodies, imitations, etc.; Tennyson, Alfred Tennyson, Baron, 1809-1892 --Parodies, imitations, etc.; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616 --Parodies, imitations, etc.
- Parodies, [ca. 1850-1950]
  - Adams, Charles Follen., 1842-1918; 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 1)
    - Beedle Yawcob Strauss, "I hafe got a leedle boy" (Box 1, Item 1)
  - Addison, Joseph, 1672-1719; 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 2)
    - Soliloguy; On Immortality, "It must be so.--Plato, thou reasonest well." (Box 1, Item 2)
    - An Ode, "The spacious firmament on high" (Box 1, Item 2)
  - Adieu, my native land, adieu! "Adieu, my native land, adieu!", 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 3)
  - Aiken, Conrad Potter., 1889-1973; 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 4)
    - Parody in the style of Aiken, original poem unidentified. (Box 1, Item 4)
  - Akenside, Mark, 1721-1770., 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 5)
    - "Inscription, 'Whoe'er thou art whose path in summer lies" (Box 1, Item 5)
  - Aldrich, James., 1810-1866; 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 6)
    - A Death Bed, "Her suffering ended with the day" (Box 1, Item 6)
  - Aldrich, Thomas Bailey, 1836-1907., 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 7)
    - Identity, "Somewhere -- in desolate wind-swept space --" (Box 1, Item 7)
    - Parody in the style of Aldrich, original poem unidentified. (Box 1, Item 7)
  - All round my hat., 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 8)
  - Allen, Elizabeth Ann (Chase) Akers., 1832-1911; 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 9)
    - Rock Me To Sleep, "Backward, turn backward, O Time in your flight" (Box 1, Item 9)
  - Arndt, Ernest Moritz, 1769-1860., 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 10)
    - The German Fatherland, "Which is the German's fatherland?" (Box 1, Item 10)
  - Arnold, Sir Edwin., 1832-1904; 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 11)
    - Parody in the style of Arnold, original poem unidentified. (Box 1, Item 11)
  - Arnold, Matthew., 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 12)
    - Artist, "whose hand, with horror wing'd, hath torn" (Box 1, Item 12)
    - Euphrosyne, "I must not say that she was true" (Box 1, Item 12)
    - Lost Masterpieces, "Still is the sea to-day" (Box 1, Item 12)
    - Morality, "We cannot kindle when we will" (Box 1, Item 12)
    - "Not here, O Apollo" (Box 1, Item 12)
    - Shakespeare, "Others abide our question. Thou are free" (Box 1, Item 12)
    - Switzerland, "Again I see my bliss at hand" (Box 1, Item 12)
    - Parodies in the style of Arnold, original poems unidentified. (Box 1, Item 12)
  - Arnold, Samuel James, 1774-1852., 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 13)
    - The Death of Nelson, "O'er Nelson's tomb, with silent grief oppress'd" (Box 1, Item 13)
  - Austin, Alfred, 1835-1913., 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 14)
    - Three Sonnets, "Now upon English soil I soon shall stand" (Box 1, Item 14)
    - "When the plover flaps" (Box 1, Item 14)
  - Aytoun, William Edmonstoune, 1813-1865., 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 15)
    - The Execution of Montrose, "Come hiter, Evan Cameron!" (Box 1, Item 15)
    - The Flight With The Snapping Turtle, "Have you heard of Philip Slingsby" (Box 1, Item 15)
  - The Bailiff's Daughter of Islington. "There was a youth, and a well-beloved youth.", 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 16)
  - Bangs, Edward., 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 17)
    - Yankee Doodle, "And there was Captain Washington" (Box 1, Item 17)
  - Bangs, John Kendrick., 1862-1922; 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 18)
    - "Dear Andrew Lang: I beg of you" (Box 1, Item 18)
  - Barbauld, Anna Letitia (Aikin)., 1743-1825; 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 19)
    - Life. "Life! I know not whose thou art" (Box 1, Item 19)
  - Barham, Richard Harris, 1788-1845., 2 envelopes (Box 1, Item 20)
    - As I Laye A-Thynkynge, "As I laye a-thynkynge, a-thynkynge, a-thynkynge" (Box 1, Item 20, Envelope 1)
    - The Babes of the Wood; or, the Norfolk Tragedy, "When we were all little and good!" (Box 1, Item 20, Envelope 1)
    - Bloudie Jacke of Shrewsberrie, "Oh! why doth thine eye gleam so bright, Bloudie Jacke?" (Box 1, Item 20, Envelope 1)
    - The Confession. "There's somewhat on my breast, father" (Box 1, Item 20, Envelope 1)
    - "A franklyn.s dogge leped over a style" (Box 1, Item 20, Envelope 1)
    - Hon. Mr. Sucklethumbkin's Story, "My Lord Tomnoddy got up on day;" (Box 1, Item 20, Envelope 1)
    - The Jackdaw of Rheims. "The Jackdaw sat on the Cardinal's chair!" (Box 1, Item 20, Envelope 1)
    - Look at the Clock, "Look at the Clock!, quoth Winifred Pryce" (Box 1, Item 20, Envelope 1)
    - Mr. Barney Maguire's Account of the Coronation, "Och! the Coronation! what celebration" (Box 1, Item 20, Envelope 1)
    - A Row in an Omnibus (Box), "Doldrum the Manager sits in the his chair" (Box 1, Item 20, Envelope 1)
    - Misadventures at Margate, "'Twas in Margate last July, I walk'd upon the pier" (Box 1, Item 20, Envelope 2)
    - Parodies in the style of Barham, original poems unidentified. (Box 1, Item 20, Envelope 2)
  - Barry, Beatrice M., 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 21)
    - Tonight. "Love me to-night! Fold your dear arms around me--" (Box 1, Item 21)
  - Bayly, Thomas Haynes., 1797-1839; 3 envelopes (Box 1, Item 22)
    - Gayly the Troubadour. "Gayly the Troubadour" (Box 1, Item 22, Envelope 1)
    - I'd Be a Butterfly. "I'd be a Butterfly born in a bower" (Box 1, Item 22, Envelope 1)
    - Long, Long Ago. "Tell me the tales that to me were so dear" (Box 1, Item 22, Envelope 1)
    - The Mistletoe Bough. "The mistletoe hung in the castle hall" (Box 1, Item 22, Envelope 1)
    - Of what is the Old Man thinking? "Of what is the Old Man thinking?" (Box 1, Item 22, Envelope 1)
    - Oh! No! We Never Mention Her. "Oh! no, we never mention her, Her name is never heard;" (Box 1, Item 22, Envelope 1)
    - The Old House at Home. "Oh! the old house at home where my forefathers dwelt" (Box 1, Item 22, Envelope 2)
    - "Out, John! out, John! what are you about, John?" (Box 1, Item 22, Envelope 2)
    - She Wore a Wreath of Roses. "She wore a wreath of roses" (Box 1, Item 22, Envelope 2)
    - The Solder's Tear. "Upon the hill he turned" (Box 1, Item 22, Envelope 2)
    - We Met. "We met-- 'twas in a crowd--" (Box 1, Item 22, Envelope 3)
    - Why Don't the Men Propose? "Why don't the men propose, mamma?" (Box 1, Item 22, Envelope 3)
    - Parodies in the style of Bayly, original poems unidentified. (Box 1, Item 22, Envelope 3)
  - Beaumont, Francis [and John Fletch, ], 1584-1616; 1579-1635; 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 23)
    - Invocation to Sleep. "Come, Sleep, and with thy sweet deceiving" (Box 1, Item 23)
  - "The Beauties of the Cambridge Fair", 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 24)
  - "Beautiful Star", 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 25)
  - Beers, Ethel Lynn, 1827-1879., 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 26)
    - The Picket Guard. "'All quiet along the Potomac,' they say" (Box 1, Item 26)
  - Begone, Dull Care. "Begone, dull Care, I prithee be gone from me;", 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 27)
  - Bellamy, W.H., 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 28)
    - Old Simon the Cellarer. "Old Simon, the cellarer, keeps a rare store--" (Box 1, Item 28)
  - Belloc, Hilaire., 1870-1953; 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 29)
    - Parodies in the style of Hilaire, original poems unidentified. (Box 1, Item 29)
  - Bennett, William Cox., 1820-1895; 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 30)
    - Parody in the style of Cox, original poem unidentified. (Box 1, Item 30)
  - Bingham, Clifton., 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 31)
    - Sing Me To Sleep. "Sing me to sleep, the shadows fall" (Box 1, Item 31)
  - Binyon, Laurence., 1869-1943; 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 32)
    - The Paralytic. "He stands whee the young faces pass and throng;" (Box 1, Item 32)
    - Parody in the style of Binyon, original poem unidentified. (Box 1, Item 32)
  - Blake, Rodney., 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 33)
    - Hoch! Der Kaiser. "Der Kaiser of dis Faterland" (Box 1, Item 33)
  - Blake, William., 1757-1827; 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 34)
    - The Fly. "Little fly" (Box 1, Item 34)
    - The Tiger. "Tiger! tiger! burning bright" (Box 1, Item 34)
  - Bloomfield, Robert., 1766-1823; 1 envelope (Box 1, Item Item)
    - Parodies in the style of Bloomfield, original poem unidentified. (Box 1, Item Item)
  - The Blue Bells of Scotland. "Oh where! and oh where! is your Highland laddie gone?", 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 36)
  - Blunt, Wilfrid Scawen.., 1840-1922; 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 37)
    - Parody in the style of Blunt, original poem unidentified. (Box 1, Item 37)
  - Boker, George Henry., 1823-1890; 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 38)
    - Parodies in the style of Boker, original poems unidentified. (Box 1, Item 38)
  - Bowen, H. Courthope., 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 39)
    - To a Doleful Poet. "Why are you sad when the sky is blue?" (Box 1, Item 39)
  - Bowring, Sir John, 1792-1872., 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 40)
    - Watchman, Tell Us Of the Night. "Watchman, tell us of the night--" (Box 1, Item 40)
  - Boyd, Percy., 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 41)
    - Wings. "Wings! to bear me over" (Box 1, Item 41)
  - Boyle, G. Courtenay., 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 42)
    - She and I. "I in the mighty palace" (Box 1, Item 42)
  - Bradley, A., 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 43)
    - "Gently touch the warbling lyre" (Box 1, Item 43)
  - Brewer, Ebenezer Cobham., 1810-1897; 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 44)
    - Little Things. "Little drops of water" (Box 1, Item 44)
  - "Brian O'Lin had no crat", 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 45)
  - The British Grenadiers. "Some talk of Alexander, and some of Hercules,", 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 46)
  - Brooks, Phillip., 1835-1893; 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 47)
    - "O Little town of Bethlehem!" (Box 1, Item 47)
  - Brown, Thomas Edward., 1830-1897; 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 48)
    - My Garden. "A garden is a lovesome thing, God wot!" (Box 1, Item 48)
  - Browning, Elizabeth (Barrett)., 1806-1861; 2 envelopes (Box 1, Item 49)
    - The Cry of the Children. "Do ye hear the children weeping, O my brothers" (Box 1, Item 49, Envelope 1)
    - "The face of the world is changed, I think" (Box 1, Item 49, Envelope 1)
    - "How do I love tee? Let me count the ways." (Box 1, Item 49, Envelope 1)
    - "I lift my heavy heart up solemnly" (Box 1, Item 49, Envelope 1)
    - Lady Geraldine's Courtship. "Dear my friend and fellow-student, I would lean my spirit o'er you!" (Box 1, Item 49, Envelope 1)
    - A Man's Requirements. "Love me, sweet, with all thou art" (Box 1, Item 49, Envelope 1)
    - A Musical Instrument. "What was he doing, the great god Pan" (Box 1, Item 49, Envelope 1)
    - My Kate. "She was not as pretty as women I know;" (Box 1, Item 49, Envelope 1)
    - "My own beloved, who hast lifted me" (Box 1, Item 49, Envelope 1)
    - Poems Before Congress. "Emperor, Emperor!" (Box 1, Item 49, Envelope 2)
    - Sonnets From the Portuguese. (Box 1, Item 49, Envelope 2)
    - "Unless you can think, when the song is done" (Box 1, Item 49, Envelope 2)
    - A Vision of Poets. "A poet could not sleep aright" (Box 1, Item 49, Envelope 2)
    - The Souls Expression. "With stammering lips and insufficient sound" (Box 1, Item 49, Envelope 2)
    - Parodies in the style of Browning, original poems unidentified. (Box 1, Item 49, Envelope 2)
  - Browning, Robert, 1812-1889., 4 envelopes (Box 1, Item 50)
    - "Brother, brother, I share the blame" (Box 1, Item 50, Envelope 1)
    - Caliban Upon Setebos; "'Will sprawl, now that the heat of day is best" (Box 1, Item 50, Envelope 1)
    - Childe Harolde. (Box 1, Item 50, Envelope 1)
    - Evelyn Hope. "Beautiful Evelyn Hope is dead!" (Box 1, Item 50, Envelope 1)
    - "Fifty years' flight! wherein should he rejoice" (Box 1, Item 50, Envelope 1)
    - Fra Lippo Lippi. "I am poor brother Lippo, by your leave" (Box 1, Item 50, Envelope 1)
    - Gold Hair. "Oh, the beautiful girl, too white" (Box 1, Item 50, Envelope 1)
    - A Grammarian's Funeral. "Let us begin and carry up the this corpse" (Box 1, Item 50, Envelope 1)
    - Home Thoughts From Abroad. "Oh, to be in England" (Box 1, Item 50, Envelope 1)
    - How They Brought the Good News From Ghent to Aix. "I sprang to the stirrup, and Joris, and he;" (Box 1, Item 50, Envelope 1)
    - James Lee. (Box 1, Item 50, Envelope 2)
    - The Last Ride Together. "I said-- Then, dearest, since 'tis so" (Box 1, Item 50, Envelope 2)
    - The Lost Leader. "Just for a handful of silver he left us" (Box 1, Item 50, Envelope 2)
    - Love Among the Ruins. "Where the quiet-colored end of evening smiles" (Box 1, Item 50, Envelope 2)
    - Mesmerism. "All I believed is true!" (Box 1, Item 50, Envelope 2)
    - The Patriot. "It was roses, roses, all the way" (Box 1, Item 50, Envelope 2)
    - The Pied Piper of Hamelin. "Hamelin Town's in Brunswick" (Box 1, Item 50, Envelope 2)
    - "Rafael made a century of sonnets" (Box 1, Item 50, Envelope 2)
    - The Ring and the Book. (Box 1, Item 50, Envelope 2)
    - Rudel to the Lady of Tripoli. (Box 1, Item 50, Envelope 2)
    - Soliloquy of the Spanish Cloister. "Gr-r-r-- there go, my heart's abhorrence!" (Box 1, Item 50, Envelope 2)
    - "Wanting is-- what?" (Box 1, Item 50, Envelope 2)
    - Waring. "What's become of Waring" (Box 1, Item 50, Envelope 2)
    - Up at a Villa-- Down in the City. "Had I but plenty of money, money enough and to spare" (Box 1, Item 50, Envelope 2)
    - The Year's at the Spring. "The year's at the Spring" (Box 1, Item 50, Envelope 2)
    - Andrea del Sarto. (Box 1, Item 50, Envelope 3)
    - At the "Mermaid". "I-- 'Next Poet?' No, my hearties" (Box 1, Item 50, Envelope 3)
    - Bishop Blougram's Apology. "No more wine? then we'll push back chairs and talk." (Box 1, Item 50, Envelope 3)
    - From 'Cherries'. "Love-making,-- how simple a matter! No depths to explore" (Box 1, Item 50, Envelope 3)
    - Marching Along. "Kentish Sir Byng stood for his King" (Box 1, Item 50, Envelope 3)
    - Memorabilia. "Ah, did you once see Shelley plain" (Box 1, Item 50, Envelope 3)
    - My Star. "All that I know" (Box 1, Item 50, Envelope 3)
    - One Word More. "There they are, my fifty men and women" (Box 1, Item 50, Envelope 3)
    - Paracelsus. (Box 1, Item 50, Envelope 3)
    - A Toccata of Galuppi's. "O, Galuppi, Baldassaro, this is very sad to find" (Box 1, Item 50, Envelope 3)
    - Parodies in the style of Browning, original poems unidentified. (Box 1, Item 50, Envelope 4)
  - Bryant, William Cullen, 1794-1889., 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 51)
    - The Future Life. "How shall I know thee in the sphere which keeps" (Box 1, Item 51)
    - The Death of the Flowers. "The melancholy days are come, the saddest of the year" (Box 1, Item 51)
    - Robert of Lincoln. "Merrily swinging on brier and weed" (Box 1, Item 51)
    - Thanatopsis. "So live, that when thy summons comes to join" (Box 1, Item 51)
    - Parodies in the style of Bryant, original poems unidentified. (Box 1, Item 51)
  - Buchanan, Robert., 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 52)
    - Parody in the style of Buchanan, original poem unidentified. (Box 1, Item 52)
  - A Bumper of Burgundy., 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 53)
  - Bunn, Alfred., 1796?-1860; 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 54)
    - "I dreamt that I dwelt in the marble halls" (Box 1, Item 54)
    - The Light of Other Days. "The light of other days is faded" (Box 1, Item 54)
    - "When other lips and other hearts" (Box 1, Item 54)
    - Parodies in the style of Bunn, original poems unidentified. (Box 1, Item 54)
  - Bunner, Henry Cuyler., 1855-1896; 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 55)
    - A Pitcher of Mignonette. "A pitcher of mignonette" (Box 1, Item 55)
    - Yes? "Is it true, then, my girl? did you mean it--" (Box 1, Item 55)
    - Parody in the style of Bunner, original poem unidentified. (Box 1, Item 55)
  - Burgess, Gelett. 1866-1951., 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 56)
    - The Purple Cow. "I never saw a purple cow" (Box 1, Item 56)
  - Burns, Robert., 1759-1796; 6 envelopes (Box 1, Item 57)
    - Address to the Deil. "O Thou! Whatever title suit thee" (Box 1, Item 57, Envelope 1)
    - Afton Water. "Flow gently, sweet Afton, among thy green braes" (Box 1, Item 57, Envelope 1)
    - Auld Lang Syne. "Should auld acquaintance be forgot" (Box 1, Item 57, Envelope 1)
    - The Cotter's Saturday Night. "My lov'd, my honoured, much respected friend!" (Box 1, Item 57, Envelope 1)
    - Duncan Gray. "Duncan Gray came here to woo" (Box 1, Item 57, Envelope 1)
    - The Farewell. "It was a' for our rightfu' King" (Box 1, Item 57, Envelope 1)
    - For A'That and A'That. "Is there, for honest poverty" (Box 1, Item 57, Envelope 2)
    - Green Grow the Rashes. "Green grow the rashes, O;" (Box 1, Item 57, Envelope 2)
    - The Happy Trio. "O, Willie brewed a peck o' maut" (Box 1, Item 57, Envelope 2)
    - Here's a Health to Them That's Away. "Here's a health to them that's awa'" (Box 1, Item 57, Envelope 2)
    - My Heart's In the Highlands. "My heart's in the Highlands, my heart is not here;" (Box 1, Item 57, Envelope 3)
    - O Whistle and I'll Come To You. "O whistle and I'll come to you, my lad" (Box 1, Item 57, Envelope 3)
    - Of A' the Airts the Wind Can Blaw. "Of a' the airts the wind can blaw" (Box 1, Item 57, Envelope 3)
    - On the Late Captain Grose's Peregrinations Thro' Scotland, "Hear, Land o' Cakes, and brither Scots" (Box 1, Item 57, Envelope 3)
    - Rattlin', Roarin' Willie. "O rattlin', roarin' Willie" (Box 1, Item 57, Envelope 3)
    - A Red, Red Rose. "O, my luve's like a red, red rose" (Box 1, Item 57, Envelope 3)
    - "Scots, wha hae wi' Wallace bled," (Bannockburn.) (Box 1, Item 57, Envelope 4)
    - Stay, My Charmer. "Stay, my charmer, can you leave me?" (Box 1, Item 57, Envelope 4)
    - Tam O'Shanter. "When chapman billies leave the street" (Box 1, Item 57, Envelope 4)
    - To a Haggis. "Fair fa' your honest, sonsie face" (Box 1, Item 57, Envelope 5)
    - To a Louse, On Seeing One On a Lady's Bonnet, At Church. "Ha! whare ye gaun, ye crawlin ferlie!" (Box 1, Item 57, Envelope 5)
    - To a Mountain Daisy. "Wee, modest, crimson-tipped flow'r" (Box 1, Item 57, Envelope 5)
    - To a Mouse, On Turning Her Up In Her Nest With the Plough, November, 1785. "Wee, sleekit, cow'rin, tim'rous beastie" (Box 1, Item 57, Envelope 5)
    - The Twa Herds. "O a ye pious godly flocks" (Box 1, Item 57, Envelope 5)
    - "Ye banks and braes o' bonie Doon" (Box 1, Item 57, Envelope 5)
    - Parodies in the style of Burns, original poems unidentified. (Box 1, Item 57, Envelope 5)
    - John Anderson, My Jo. "John Anderson, my jo, John" (Box 1, Item 57, Envelope 6)
    - John Barleycorn. "There was three Kings into the east" (Box 1, Item 57, Envelope 6)
    - McPherson's Farewell. "Farewell, ye dungeons dark and strong" (Box 1, Item 57, Envelope 6)
    - Man Was Made To Mourn. "When chill November's surly blast" (Box 1, Item 57, Envelope 6)
  - Burnand, Sir Francis Cowley., 1836-1917; 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 58)
    - True To Poll. "I'll sing you a song, not very long" (Box 1, Item 58)
  - Burton, Robert, 1577-1640., 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 59)
    - The Abstract of Melancholy. "When I go musing all alone" (Box 1, Item 59)
  - Busby, Thomas., 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 60)
    - Parodies in the style of Busby, original poems unidentified. (Box 1, Item 60)
  - Bushnell, Dr. Samuel G., 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 61)
    - On the Aristocracy of Harvard. "I come from good old Boston" (Box 1, Item 61)
  - Butler, William Allen., 1825-1902; 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 62)
    - Miss Flora McFlimsey. "Mis Flora McFlimsey, of Madison Square" (Box 1, Item 62)
  - "By the sad sea waves, I listen while they moan", 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 63)
  - Byrom, John, 1692-1763., 1 envelope (Box 1, Item 64)
    - "My time, O ye Muses, was happily spent" (Box 1, Item 64)
  - Byron, George Gordon Noël Byron, 6th baron., 1788-1824; 7 envelopes (Box 2, Item 1)
    - "Adieu, adieu! my native shore" (Box 2, Item 1, Envelope 1)
    - "The castled crag of Drachenfels" (Box 2, Item 1, Envelope 1)
    - Childe Harold. (Box 2, Item 1, Envelope 1)
    - Darkness. "I had a dream, which was not at all a dream." (Box 2, Item 1, Envelope 1)
    - The Destruction of Sennacherib. "The Assyrian came down like the wolf on the fold" (Box 2, Item 1, Envelope 1)
    - "Didst ever see a gondola? For fear" (Box 2, Item 1, Envelope 2)
    - Don Juan. (Box 2, Item 1, Envelope 2)
    - English Bards, Etc. "Still must I hear? - shall hoarse Fitzgerald bawl" (Box 2, Item 1, Envelope 2)
    - Fare Thee Well, "Fare thee well! and if for ever" (Box 2, Item 1, Envelope 2)
    - The First Kiss of Love. "Away With your fictions of flimsy romance;" (Box 2, Item 1, Envelope 2)
    - "He who hath bent him o'er the dead" (Box 2, Item 1, Envelope 2)
    - "I see before me the Gladiator lie:" (Box 2, Item 1, Envelope 2)
    - "I stood in Venice on the the Bridge of Sighs" (Box 2, Item 1, Envelope 2)
    - I Would I Were a Careless Child. "I would I were a careless child" (Box 2, Item 1, Envelope 2)
    - "The isles of Greece, the isles of Greece!* (Box 2, Item 1, Envelope 3)
    - "Know ye the land where the cypress and the myrtle" (Box 2, Item 1, Envelope 4)
    - Lachin Y Gair. "Away ye gardens of roses!" (Box 2, Item 1, Envelope 4)
    - Maid of Athens, Ere We Part. "Maid of Athens, ere we part" (Box 2, Item 1, Envelope 5)
    - Mazeppa. (Box 2, Item 1, Envelope 5)
    - "Mont Blanc is the monarch of mountains;" (Box 2, Item 1, Envelope 5)